（小泉(こいずみ)夫人）月本(つきもと)君？
Tsukimoto?
You're Tsukimoto, aren't you?
あなた 月本君じゃない？
You've come to check up on my husband?
主人の見舞いに来てくれたのね
うれしいわ
I appreciate that.
They say he overworked his muscles.
筋肉痛ですって
And to think he's over seventy!
70過ぎた おじいちゃんがよ
Come on in.
さあ 入って
あの人 きっと喜ぶわ
I'm sure he'll be glad to see you.
Actually, um... if he's okay, then never mind.
（スマイル）いえ あの…
大丈夫なら もう大丈夫です
I'm about to make dinner. Stay and have a bite.
（小泉夫人）夕食作るから
食べていらっしゃい
I don't enjoy eating in other people's homes.
（スマイル）
よその家で食事するの
苦手なんです
I see. So that's how it is.
そう そういう感じね
And you must have it rough, with a strange old man pestering you.
あなたも変な老人に
追いかけ回されて 大変ね
Yes. He's a huge pain.
ええ 大変迷惑しています
ウフッ
あなた ホント
かわいげのない子ね
There's really no charm to you, is there?
I'm sorry.
すみません
I find that wonderful.
ステキよ とても
Do come by again.
また来てちょうだいね
I will.
また 来ます
待ってるわ
I'll be waiting.
かわいらしい子ね
目元が涼しげで
What an adorable boy.
Such clear eyes.
（小泉）
いずれ あの子は怪物に化ける
He'll become a monster someday.
The chrysalis is about to burst open.
さなぎの体は はち切れそうだ
私は ただ—
All I have to do is give him a little push.
そっと彼の背中を
押してやればいいんだよ
We're counting on you again for this year's Interhigh, Ryuuichi.
（風間(かざま)理事長）
今年のインターハイも
頼んだぞ 竜一(りゅういち)
In victory is where we find truth.
勝利の中にこそ真実がある
We need you to spread the word of the quality of
our products by being successful at a global level.
お前には
世界で活躍してもらって—
うちの製品の良さを
広めてもらわないとな
Yes, sir!
But I'm worried about the team competition.
しかし 団体戦に不安があります
Close any chinks in your armor while
they're small, or cut off the entire part.
（風間理事長）ほころびは
小さいうちに とじるか切り捨てろ
（ドラゴン）片瀬(かたせ)高校に—
There's a chopper at Katase High who bothers me.
気になるカットマンが
いるのであります
Katase? Koizumi's school...
（風間理事長）片瀬？ 小泉か
Is this chopper good?
そいつは強いのか
I don't know yet.
まだ分かりません！
If he is, bring him here.
（風間理事長）よければ連れてこい
お前と卓(たく)に任せる
I'll leave it to you and Taku.
押忍！
Yes, sir!
Compromising is like cutting off your own arm.
妥協は腕を切り落とすに等しい
If we lose, you take responsibility.
負けたら お前が責任を取れ
Yes, sir!
押忍！
Tamura Table Tennis
Yeah!
（ペコ）っしゃあ！
It's about three centuries too soon for you to challenge me.
３世紀 早まったね
俺に挑戦するの
（オババ）小泉とスマイルがねえ
Koizumi and Smile, huh?
気に入らねえな どうも
I don't like that one bit.
A new age has dawned, and still I can't make a decision
My path is too straight for my taste, but I'll walk it
I can't choose just yet
I have to think about it
I have no idea what I want to do
I'm going crazy!
Comparing yourself to others just makes you depressed
You're alone in this world
You're always alone here
Still you're gonna do it, right?
Maybe there's nothing that only I can do
But there's no way that I
But there's no way that I won't try to leave my mark
I just want to have my fun, whatever the times
Testing, testing.
Hey, isn't that Kaiou?
（生徒）おい あれ海王(かいおう)じゃね？
（生徒）海王 来たよ
Kaiou's here.
I do have eyes, y'know.
（生徒）見りゃ分かるよ
（生徒）すげえ頭だ
Whoa, check out their heads.
Where did you go, Mr. Tsukimoto?
どこへ行ったんだ ミスター月本
Interhigh - Kanagawa Prefecture Preliminaries
What's wrong, Wenge? You homesick?
Heh, something like that.
How's the bracket looking?
（ペコ）どう？ 組み合わせ
（スマイル）
最悪　３回戦でコン・ウェンガ
They suck. I'll play Kong Wenge in the third round.
My condolences.
あら そりゃ ご愁傷さま
ペコは？
What about you?
Pesky opponent in the quarterfinals, but if I beat him, I'll be in the top four and go to nationals.
準々の相手が
ちと うるさいけど—
それ たたきゃ
ベスト４ 残って全国よ
Oh, speak of the devil.
あっ 来たよ 準々の相手
Well, if it isn't Peco!
（アクマ）
おーよ！ ペコじゃねえか
眼中に入らんかったよ
Whoops, I didn't see you there.
ああ？ 誰だよ てめえ
'Scuze me?! Who the hell are you?!
ポンコツ校で せいぜい
天狗(てんぐ)んなってろや スカタン
Play big fish all you want in
your little-pond school, idiot.
ブランド校のコバンザメ
Better than leeching off a branded school.
No, I'm playing in the first game.
いいや
先鋒(せんぽう) 任されてんよ 俺ってば
What?!
（ペコ）何ぃ？
Sakuma, meeting time!
（卓）佐久間(さくま) ミーティングするぞ
バス 戻れ
Get back to the bus!
（アクマ）押忍！
Yes, sir!
スマイル
Smile, you still followin' Peco wherever he goes?
まだペコに 金魚のフンみてえに
くっついてんのかよ
Say hi to the old lady for me.
タムラのオババに よろしくな
I will.
伝えとく
（アクマ）
ハンカチ用意しとけ ペコ
Get your handkerchief ready, Peco.
お前 負けんと すぐ泣くかんよ
You always cry when you lose.
（ペコ）
メガネ割るぞ　てめえ コラァ！
I'll smash your glasses, damn it!
海王の先鋒だって
He's playing the first game for Kaiou.
ふん！
You know them?
（卓）知り合いか？
Yes, sir!
（アクマ）押忍！ 昔 同じ道場に
通ったやつらであります
We used to attend the same table tennis hall.
I don't see Kazama around.
ああ… 風間先輩の姿が
見えないのでありますが
Don't worry about him.
（卓）気にするな
やつなら便所だ
He's in the restroom.
The restroom?
（アクマ）便所？
You'll understand his pain someday.
お前にも いつか
あの子の つらさが分かる
I can't believe I have to play them. They're like kids messing around.
Get changed, Wenge. You're up soon.
You wanna play instead?
You could win.
You're not a spectator. You should take this seriously.
（スマイル）ニーハオ
Ni hao.
It's that kid. I'll go check him out.
Heh, suddenly I feel like there's some hope.
（生徒）おい あれコンじゃね？
Hey, isn't that Kong?
Nice, the brooding handsome type.
（生徒）渋いね カッコいい
（生徒）
お手並み拝見！ 代表レベル
Let's see what you've got, rep!
Dude, I doubt he speaks Japanese.
（生徒）
どうせ日本語 分からないんだろ？
Hey, China, look here!
（生徒）
チャイナ！ こっち見れえ！
（ドラゴン）静粛に願う！
Quiet!
彼に対する誹謗(ひぼう)中傷は
不愉快極まりない
Nothing pisses me off more than hearing slander directed at him.
（生徒）誰？ あのハゲ
（生徒）シーッ
Who's the baldy?
Shh!
海王の風間だ　君と語らいたい
I'm Kazama of Kaiou.
I wish to speak with you.
Isn't Kaiou in a meeting right now?
海王は
ミーティング中じゃないですか？
Am I bothering you?
迷惑か？
フッ 露骨に感情が顔に出る人だ
You wear your emotions all over your face.
What an awesome drive.
（生徒）すげえドライブだな
（生徒）真横に逃げんぞ
It's going dead sideways!
Game goes to Kong! Eleven-love!
（主審）ゲーム トゥ コン選手
イレブンラブ
Jouhoku's Murata couldn't even score a single point.
（生徒）
城北(じょうほく)の村田(むらた)が１点も取れねえ
With such a gulf in skill between them,
it's hard to tell exactly how good Kong is.
これだけ実力差があると—
かえって
コン君の実力が見極めづらいね
He went too far.
やりすぎです あれは
A person can't bounce back from being
crushed like that in front of so many people.
こんな大勢の面前で—
あんな飛ばされ方したら
立ち直れない
You're a kind soul.
優しいんだね 君は
It's not like that.
そういうことじゃない
ならば 余裕か？
Supreme confidence, then?
Yes!
Kong knows the terror of table tennis more than anyone else.
（ドラゴン）コン君は誰よりも—
卓球の怖さを知っている人間だよ
ナショナルチームから
落ちたことで—
His life changed when he was kicked off the national team.
彼の人生は一変した
この島国で
プレーすることなど—
I'm sure playing in this tiny country is the furthest thing from what he wants.
まったく彼の本意ではないだろう
日本を制すれば
本国復帰の見通しも立つ
If he conquers Japan, he may be able to make a comeback in his own country.
But if he loses, forget China—he'll
have a hard time even staying here.
しかし 負ければ—
復帰どころか
日本に とどまることすら困難だ
それは
選手生命の終わりを意味する
Which would mean the end of his career.
私はね 月本君
You know, Tsukimoto, I hate the way you play.
君のプレーが嫌いだ
Your technique is magnificent,
確かに技術は 素晴らしい
but it disgusts me to watch you always consider your opponent's feelings.
だが 相手の心情を考慮して打つ
君の卓球は実に醜い
君には
ラケットを握る資格などない
You are not fit to hold a racket.
I despise it.
私は嫌悪する
I don't appreciate you stating that so bluntly.
そう はっきり言われると
さすがに不愉快です
風間さん そろそろ
Kazuma, we should get going.
I'm coming.
おう 今 行く
Match goes to Kong!
（主審）マッチ トゥ コン選手
（村田）クソ！
Damn it.
Now I kind of wanna go home!
（生徒）
なんか帰りたくなっちゃった 俺
Murata didn't last ten minutes.
（生徒）
10分っきゃもたなかったよ 村田
（生徒）哀れだ
That was sad.
頼むよ ミスター月本
Please, Mr. Tsukimoto.
Just don't hold back when you play.
手を抜いて打つのだけは
やめておくれな
君の悪いクセだ
It's a bad habit of yours.
It's okay, Coach.
大丈夫ですよ 先生
絶対 勝ちます
I will win.
If you want to request how, tell me now.
注文があれば言ってください
By five points? Two points? Skunk him? Anything.
５点　２点　スコンク　何だって
Oh, I know. Kong won in ten minutes.
（スマイル）
そうだ コンが10分で倒したんだ
I'll get it done in five.
僕は５分で片づけよう
Did something happen?
何かあったのかね
I just want to win, Coach.
勝ちたいだけですよ 先生
いけませんか？
Is that wrong?
No.
いや 大変よい
It's great.
You're not usually so hard on people.
（アクマ）風間さんが あんな
厳しいこと言うの珍しいですね
It'll be good for him.
いい薬ですよ
大体 やつは昔から…
He's always up on his high horse—
（ドラゴン）君は月本君を
よく知っているんだったな
You know Tsukimoto well, don't you?
何とか彼を
うちに呼べないものかな
Could you ask him to come to our school?
Next year will be rough if I'm the only good player.
来年 私一枚では きついだろ
やあ コン君
ニーハオ ニーハオ
Hello, Kong.
Ni hao, ni hao.
Come on, Wenge. That was Kazama!
I don't like guys like him.
Just gonna ignore us, you jerk?!
（アクマ）
シカトかよ　おお？ コラァ！
（江上(えがみ)の声）片高(かたこう) 月本？
Katase High's Tsukimoto?
Here.
（江上）ほい
（スマイル）はい
Here.
Don't know him.
（江上の声）知らねえな
A pretty decent chopper, eh?
一丁前(いっちょまえ)にカットマンか
Good luck.
（江上）よろしくな
（スマイル）こちらこそ
Same to you.
This is my last tournament.
（江上の声）何しろ これが最後
３度目の正直
I won't lose my third tournament to a first-year.
１年坊やにゃ負けねえよ
Ready!
（主審）レディー
Man, I'd like to go to nationals...
（江上の声）行きてえな 全国
He's a chopper, so I guess I'll serve
short to his fore and scope him out.
カットマンなら とりあえず
フォアにショート入れて様子見っか
リターン甘く来たら
バックに３球目攻撃
If he gives me an easy return, I'll hit three to his backhand.
そのあとは えっと…
Then I'll... uh...
I'll worry about that when I get there.
そん時 考えよ
（江上）え？
（主審）ラブワン
Love-one!
He's a fast attacker!
こいつ 速攻！？
あの野郎 前で さばく気か
He plans to play close to the table?
Is he conserving energy?
He sure is confident.
He's provoking me.
（江上の声）
挑発？ ナメとんのか
Underestimating me?
いちいち切らねえで
とっとと決めちまう腹だ
He wants to settle this fast instead of bothering with chopping.
ガーン
Damn, he's getting me down.
ホント 悲しくなっちゃうよ
His rubber's not even meant for quick attacks.
ほんでも
ラバーは速攻用じゃねえし—
I'll hit it normally this time!
次は普通に…
Love-two!
（主審）ラブツー
This isn't working.
（江上の声）ダメだ こりゃ
This game is over.
リターンでノータッチかよ
He didn't even touch that return.
卓球ではないな
This isn't table tennis.
Reality always turns its cold shoulder to me.
（江上の声）現実は
いつだって俺にゃ冷てえや
Well, I stuck with this longer than most things.
飽きっぽい俺にゃ よく続いたよ
Three years of plugging at it in my naturally gloomy way.
根暗にコツコツ３年間
Should I go to the beach?
海行くか　それも悪くねえ
That's not a bad idea.
Match goes to Tsukimoto!
（主審）マッチ トゥ 月本選手
（山田(やまだ)）野郎 とんだタヌキだ
He's one sly bastard.
I can't believe he's had that sweet offensive game up his sleeve.
（大田(おおた)）あんな すげえ速攻
隠し持ってやがった
That was a sloppy offensive.
雑な速攻だな
気晴らしです
I needed to unwind.
You couldn't have picked another way to do it?
別の方法は ないのかね
Table tennis to kill time, and offensive play to unwind.
暇つぶしの卓球
気晴らしの速攻です
卓球に人生 懸けるなんて
ナンセンス
Devoting your life to table tennis is nonsense.
It's beyond comprehension.
理解に苦しむ
It's creepy.
気味が悪い
Tsukimoto Makoto. He's a first-year.
When do we dance?
If all goes well, the third round.
The one after next, then.
Maybe I'll go to the beach.
（江上の声）海
Devoting your life to
table tennis is creepy
行くか
The best part of these popsicles is that even the stew-flavored ones still have the crunchy parts.
（ペコ）
ガリガリ君は シチュー味でも—
ちゃんとガリガリ部分を
残してんのがいいんだよね
近頃 自分を見失ってんのが
多すぎんよ
Unlike all those people who are
losing sight of themselves lately.
Come on, now!
クソ！ 暑が夏いぜ
This summer's getting heated!
（ピー子(こ)）
過程が大切だって 私 思うの
I think going through the process is important.
Screw the process!
（ポー）家庭が何だ
男は見えだ！
A man needs his pride!
Forfeiting would be far more embarrassing.
棄権するほうが よっぽど恥よ
But Chinese players are really good!
だって 中国の選手は強いんだぜ
Being Chinese doesn't automatically mean he's good.
中国人だからって
強いとは限らないわ
There are Africans who can't dance, you know.
ダンスの苦手なアフリカ人だって
いるもの
それに私
負けても立ち向かうポー君が好き
Plus I like you for facing challenges you might lose, Po.
ピー子
Piiko...
He may have played for his country, but he's a dropout.
（ピー子）代表クラスったって
落ちこぼれのポンポコピーよ
Really?
（ポー）ホント？
（ピー子）勝つチャンスはあるわよ
You have a shot at winning.
（ポー）やつはポンポコピー？
He's a dropout?
Match goes to Kong!
（主審）マッチ トゥ コン選手
Of course...
（ポー）んなわけ…
（ピー子）ねえな
...not.
Tsujidou Academy
Kong Wenge
Katase High
Tsukimoto Makoto
Kaiou Academy
Sakuma Manabu
Oh yeah!
シャラッ！
Katase High
Hoshino Yutaka
（卓）お疲れ
Good work.
押忍！
Thanks.
Kaiou Academy
Kazama Ryuuichi
Advancing
to the
Third
Round
Advancing
to the
Third
Round
（ペコ）余裕だな
You seem confident.
得意のカットを使わねえのも
そのせいか？
Is that why you're not using your chop?
Does it bother you?
気に障る？
I guess.
まあな
Offensive play is my specialty, you know.
速攻は俺のオハコだかんな
Then write your name on it nice and clear.
だったら見えやすいとこに
名前 書いときなよ
"Demon" seems different from when he was at Tamura.
アクマは
タムラの時とは違うみたいだ
Be careful.
気をつけたほうがいい
楽勝ベイビー　任せんしゃい
Piece of cake, baby!
I'd win in my sleep.
本気？
You serious?
You're really stuck on this.
やけに絡むね
何かあったんかい？
Did something happen?
Do you believe in heroes?
ペコはヒーロー信じる？
When I'm in trouble, he always comes to save me.
ピンチの時には
必ず助けに来てくれるんだ
僕が どんなに深く
閉じ込められていても
No matter how deep the hole I'm trapped in.
Yeah, right. No way someone like that exists.
ハッ そんなもんいるかい
漫画の世界だよ
That only happens in comics.
To protect the peace on Earth
Here
from
planet
Ping
Pong!
Here
from
planet
Ping
Pong!
I believed.
僕は信じてた
No one
can
beat
me
No one
can
beat
me
the hero of
righteousness
That's me
もう ずっと長いこと
彼が来るのを待っていた
I've been waiting for him for a long time.
The totally
invincible hero
is me!
The totally
invincible hero
is me!
My name is
Whatever, just don't randomly change your play style.
とにかく 戦型は気安く変えるな
You'll develop weird habits.
変なクセつくぞ
My name is
Okay.
（小泉）これで勝負してこい
Play him with this.
これ ツブ高(だか)じゃないですか
This is a long pips-out.
I switched out your usual one.
貼り替えておいたよ
I'm not ready for this yet.
まだ無理ですよ これ
Just try it out.
なら 試せ
I'm playing Kong.
コンですよ
Got a problem?
不足かね？
イエス
Yes.
I haven't felt like this in a while. I'm nervous.
Just play like you always do.
I kind of like the feeling, actually.
月本とコンが打ちますよ 風間さん
Tsukimoto and Kong are about to play, Kazama.
Yeah.
１つ聞いて
よろしいでしょうか
Can I ask you something?
Yeah.
You seem quite interested in Tsukimoto.
月本のこと—
ずいぶん気にして
おられますが なぜ…
Why?
Hmm... That's a little complicated.
うーん そのあたり 少し複雑でな
何しろ 才能とは求める人間のみに
与えられるものではないのでな
The thing is, talent isn't something
that only goes to those who want it.
（スマイル）頑張れよ コンさん
Do your best, Kong.
I'm good.
強いよ 僕は
（中国語の
チャイナの声）
Is that the best you can do after all?
Yes!
Blame your environment.
（中国語の
チャイナの声）
You have no rival, no master, no pressure!
You'll get rusty in this greenhouse environment.
Just like an old bike tossed in the river.
However,
I have a place to return to!
A bountiful country!
（主審）フォルト
Fault!
Game goes to Kong!
ゲーム トゥ コン選手
Even our prince doesn't stand a chance against China.
我らが王子も中国相手だと…
This is the best we can do.
こんなもんですよ
Wenge, your play is sloppy.
He's nothing. He can barely return the ball.
But he—
I expected too much. He's no different.
That's the best you can expect
of this country's players.
（チャイナ）フンッ
Don't worry. I'll beat him straight up.
Yes!
Five-seven!
（主審）ファイブセブン
Six-seven!
シックスセブン
Good.
（小泉）グッド！
He's got Kong anticipating the wrong strokes.
コンは 待ちを
外されるようになりましたね
Yeah.
He's reading you like a book, Wenge!
Don't shout.
いいかげん
前に出て勝負したら どうなんだい
How about you finally step up and compete?
You always withdraw into your shell, Mr. Tsukimoto.
すぐ自分の殻に閉じこもるのね
ミスター月本
Game goes to Tsukimoto!
（主審）ゲーム トゥ 月本選手
Eleven-seven!
イレブンセブン
Damn it!
Talent, huh?
才能か
Perfect.
（小泉）パーフェクト
I hear China might lose!
（生徒）
負けそうだってよ 例のチャイナ
Who is he playing?
（生徒）相手 誰？
（生徒）何か 片高の…
Some guy from Katase High.
He's a first-year.
１年ですな
Really?
へえ そうですか
There's another amazing kid.
また すげえの出てきたな
（主審）イレブンシックス
ゲーム トゥ 月本選手
Eleven-six! Game goes to Tsukimoto!
Can he... predict my movements?
心の動揺がプレーを乱すのだよ
コン君
Your agitation is throwing off your play, Kong.
He was inputting Kong's data during that first game.
序盤はコンのデータを
インプットしてやがったんだ
He's like a precision machine.
正確無比のマシン
（オババ）
いよいよスマイルが
本性 出してきたね
Smile's finally revealing his true nature.
You can't smoke in...
禁煙…
No way.
ウソだろ？ 勝つのか？
Is he going to win?
Damn it!
（主審）エイトフォー
Eight-four!
おいおい
こりゃもしかすると もしかするぜ
Whoa, whoa.
This might just happen!
Tsukimoto looks so awesome right now.
（大田）月本のやつ—
えれえカッコいいことに
なってますね
This is it, Wenge!
Be ready, because if you lose this match, it's all over!
I thought you were going to teach
the team that dropped you a lesson!
Quit strutting and get real!
Answer me!
Yes, sir.
You're not in Japan to see the sights, moron!
エイッ！
Yes!
Eight-five.
（主審）エイトファイブ
（アクマ）
なんで あんな
浮ついた球 返すんだ
Why'd he make such a lame return?
Good grief.
What happened with China?
（生徒）例のチャイナ
Looks like he'll win in the end.
（生徒）結局 勝つみたい
The first-year is just defending now.
（男性）
何か防戦一方になりましたね
１年の子
Yeah.
（男性）ですね
（生徒）
かわいかったよね １年の子
I thought that first-year was cute.
I so hear you!
（生徒）分かる それ！
体力差でしょ 要するに
It came down to a difference in endurance.
（主審）マッチ トゥ コン選手
Match goes to Kong!
Kong Wenge Advances
to the Fourth Round
Tsukimoto Makoto
Eliminated in
the Third Round
（江上）海へ—
I made it
来た
to the beach.
A red sun stares at me
The world goes blurry when I yawn
My wishes fluctuate like a metronome
Everything tells me this is the end
I do have some dreams, you know
Sometimes we breathe
and just seem to inhale the smoke of someone
somewhere out of sight
Then all our great energy just seems to melt away
I don't understand this wonderland
I won't get wet even if it rains
This is a wonderland
Once I've made it through this long tunnel
I'm sure that someone will kiss me